{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "Following the signing of a petition named for this area, John Bowne illegally housed Quakers in his home. William Steinway of Steinway & Sons built the Steinway Village in this area’s Astoria neighborhood. Thirty people signed the Flushing Remonstrance in this borough against Director-General Peter Stuyvesant. This borough is the sight of the Unisphere, built for the 1964 New York World’s Fair. For ten points, name this New York City Borough, the location of John F. Kennedy International Airport.",
      "answer": "Queens A"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man was legendarily scolded by a peasant woman after letting her griddle cakes burn. This leader’s father, Aethelwulf, sent him to Rome to be coronated by Pope Leo IV. He isn’t William the Conqueror, but this king compiled his law code in the “Doom Book.” This leader forced the Danish King, Guthrum, to convert to Christianity after defeating him at the Battle of Eddington. For ten points, name this “Great” King of Wessex.",
      "answer": "Alfred The Great"
    },
    {
      "question": "Testimony by this man was used by the Supreme Court in the Betamax Case which dealt with theRhome video market, leading to approval of PBS funding. This Presbyterian minister also worked in television and offered children relief during the First Gulf War and the Invasion of Iraq. Daniel Tiger, HenriettaPussycatandKingFridayfeatureonthisman’sshow.Fortenpoints,namethiscardigan-wearing creator of a PBS show titled for his namesake “Neighborhood.”",
      "answer": [
        "Mr. Rogers",
        "Fred Rogers"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Despite losing most of his money in an Algerian oil deal, this man refused to appear in alcohol and cigarette commercials, claiming it would be a bad influence. This man’s autobiography To Hell and Back Dwas adapted into a movie in which he starred. This man slept with a loaded gun under his pillow as indication of his PTSD after single-handedly holding off hundreds of Germans in the Colmar Pocket. For ten points, name this Medal of Honor winner and movie star.",
      "answer": "Audie Murphy"
    },
    {
      "question": "In order to downplay a defeat, this country’s Gothic Line was renamed to the Green Line by Albert Kesselring. This country’s forces faced Operation Avenger in which bombers controversially destroyed the historic abbey of Monte Cassino. A dead body with false war plans was floated ashore prior to the invasion of this country in Operation Husky. This country’s capital fell on June 5th, 1944 after an offensive from Anzio. For ten points, Mark Clark controversially captured what country’s capital in 1944?",
      "answer": "Italy T"
    },
    {
      "question": "Ismail al-Azhari was the first prime minister of this country, where the Anyanya rebels fought a civil war from 1955 to 1972 that was ended by the Addis Ababa Agreement. The Nuer White Army enlisted child soldiers during this country’s Second Civil War which ended in 2005. The Justice and Equality Movement are fighting the Janjaweed in, for ten points, what African country led by Omar al-Bashir F whose Southern neighbor seceded in 2011?",
      "answer": [
        "Republic of the Sudan",
        "North Sudan,"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "During this man’s early career as the Allied head of Combined Operations, he planned both the successful bombing of St. Nazaire and the disastrous Dieppe Raid. This man hired Cyril Radcliffe to form a line of partition to separate the Muslim League and the Indian National Congress following independence. For ten points, identify British India’s last Viceroy who was assassinated by the IRA when A a bomb exploded aboard his fishing boat.",
      "answer": [
        "Louis Mountbatten",
        "1st Earl Mountbatten of Burma"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "During a civil war in this country, the HMS Orestes faced fire from both sides and a commander using the alias “Carlos de Ponza” led the navy. Miguel I entered exile after this country’s Liberal Wars. After this country’s King Sebastian died at Alcacer Quibir, this country entered a union with its neighbor until the Restoration War. Like Spain, French forces invaded this country in the Peninsular War. The House of Braganza ruled, for ten points, what Iberian country? R",
      "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Xenophon’s version of this event, the central figure refused the aid of his friends because the possibility of death was better than senility. According to one source of this event, the central figure offered to pay a fine of 30 mina as an alternative to banishment and execution. As a result of this event, a certain philosopher was forced to drink hemlock. For ten points, name this event where the teacher of Plato was convicted of the corruption of the youth of Athens.",
      "answer": [
        "Trial of Socrates",
        "apology of Socrates,",
        "equivalents to “Trial,” do NOT D",
        "or"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This man headed off Napoleon III’s attempt to annex Hawaii with the statement that his country would not “stand for any such action.” This man unsuccessfully ran for president on the ticket of the Know-Nothing Party in the election of 1856. This man dismissed his predecessor’s cabinet and took the lead in pushing through Henry Clay’s proposals in the Compromise of 1850. For ten points, name the last Whig president of the United States who succeeded Zachary Taylor.",
      "answer": "Millard Fillmore T"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The League of Augsburg was formed to combat this man who was forced to sign the Treaty of Ryswick after the Nine Years’ War. This man solidifieFd his rule after the Treaties of Rastatt and Utrecht ended The Fronde which was prompted by his attempts to gain control of the Spanish Throne. For ten points name this French monarch who fought the War of the Spanish Succession and was known as the “Sun King.”",
        "answer": [
          "Louis XIV",
          "Louis the Great,"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Louis XIV was only 4 when his father died and this woman, his mother, annulled her husband’s will and became Regent of France with the support of Cardinal Mazarin. A",
        "answer": "Anne of Austria"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Jesse Jackson drew controversy in this election year for using an anti-Semitic slur in New York City during his candidacy for the Democratic nomination. That nomination was eventually won by a man who lampooned a rival by referencing Wendy’s “Where’s the Beef” ads. The first woman to appear on a major party presidential ticket, Geraldine Ferraro, ran in this year. For ten points, name this election year in which only the District of Columbia and Minnesota voted for Walter Mondale over Ronald Reagan.",
        "answer": "1984 R"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Colorado senator was the target of Mondale’s “Where’s the Beef?” barb. He tried to run for President again in 1987, but his apparent affair with campaign aide Donna Rice caused a media frenzy that forced him to withdraw.",
        "answer": "Gary Hart"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Irving Langmuir conducted his Nobel-winning research at this company, whose namesake “Realty Plots” were acquired from Union College during the 19th century. In the 1980s, a CEO of this company D popularized “rank and yank” policies while re-acquiring RCA. This company was one of the original 12 members of the Dow Jones Industrial Average and has been led by Jeff Immelt and Jack Welch. For ten points, name this U.S. conglomerate founded by Thomas Edison.",
        "answer": [
          "General Electric Company",
          "G.E."
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "G.E. is headquartered in this city near the confluence of the Hudson and Mohawk rivers, the site of a 1690 namesake massacre of residents by French soldiers and their Native American allies.",
        "answer": "Schenectady, New York T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A group of students rallied in support of this event at the Paul Sauve Arena. During this event, one politician stated “go on and bleed” to “weak-kneed bleeding hearts” before telling Tim Ralfe, “Just watch me.” This event saw the kidnapping of British diplomat James Cross and the execution of Pierre Laporte. The War Measures Act suspended civil liberties during this event by Prime Minister Pierre Trudeau. For F ten points, name this 1970 crisis started by the Front de Liberation du Quebec.",
        "answer": [
          "October Crisis",
          "La Crise d’Octobre,",
          "FLQ crisis"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Late in life, Pierre Trudeau was diagnosed with this degenerative disorder of the central nervous system that also afflicted George H.W. Bush and boxer Muhammad Ali.",
        "answer": "Parkinson’s Disease A"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This university was originally founded in a town named for the naval hero Peter Warren. The father of the man for whom this university was re-named was involved in smuggling and the slave trade. The creation of this university was supported by the First Baptist Church of America and was proposed in a petition drafted by three inhabitants of Newport. Located in the same state as Roger Williams University, for ten points, name this Ivy League institution originally named the College of Rhode Island.",
        "answer": [
          "Brown University BORNUS: One of Brown’s many noted alumni is this entrepreneur and philanthropist, the author of The War on Normal People, who ran for the 2020 Democratic presidential nomination ANSWER: Andrew Yang 6 One side in this battle was forced to retreat after a heavy storm at Wiehen rendered their bows unusable. The losing side in this battle withdrew to the Kalkriese Hills, only to be ambushed by the spy Hermann, also known as Arminius. Reports of this battle allegedly prompted emperor Augustus to shout, “Varus, give me back my legions!” For ten points, name this 9 AD battle in which a Roman army was D ambushed in the forests of Germany. ANSWER: Battle of the Teutoberg Forest",
          "Varian Disaster before “Varus”"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The earliest references to the Battle of the Teutoberg Forest may have come from the Tristia, written by this author of the Metamorphoses during his exile from Rome.",
        "answer": "Ovid T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In one song from this musical, a woman asks “Should I bring him down? Should I scream and shout?” In another song, the protagonist of this musical is asked “Who are you? What have you sacrificed?” by a choir of angels. This musical was banned in South Africa and has been condemned by both Jews and Christians. This musical features the musical number “Pilate’s Dream.” For ten points, name this rock F musical based on the life of a New Testament figure, composed by Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber.",
        "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Another Biblically-based musical, the first collaboration of Lloyd Webber and Rice to be performed on stage, is this story based on Genesis, chapters 37-50, which includes the song “Benjamin Calypso.”",
        "answer": "Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat A"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "United States Air Force",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "City in a western US state in which its Academy was founded F",
          "answer": "Colorado Springs, Colorado"
        },
        {
          "question": "Highest scoring American World War One flying ace, also a race car driver",
          "answer": "Eddie Rickenbacker"
        },
        {
          "question": "Iconic bomber of the Eighth Air Force, one of whose surviving examples is the Memphis Belle",
          "answer": "Boeing B-17 Flying Fortress A"
        },
        {
          "question": "Failed sustained Vietnam War bombing campaign from 1965-68",
          "answer": "Operation Rolling Thunder"
        },
        {
          "question": "Controversial aviation officer who supported airpower over battleships",
          "answer": "William “Billy” Mitchell"
        },
        {
          "question": "Area during the Korean War known for fierce air combat with namesake Soviet jet fighters",
          "answer": "MiG Alley R"
        },
        {
          "question": "Highest scoring American World War Two ace, who flew P-38s in the Pacific",
          "answer": "Richard “Dick” Bong"
        },
        {
          "question": "Series of air attacks against the Ploesti oilfields in World War Two which resulted in heavy bomber losses",
          "answer": "Operation Tidal Wave D T"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "House of Capet",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Kingdom that they ruled from Paris F",
          "answer": "France"
        },
        {
          "question": "Founder of the dynasty, elected to succeed the Carolingians",
          "answer": "Hugh Capet"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capetian captured during the Seventh Crusade, later made a saint",
          "answer": "Louis IX"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capetian who withdrew from the Third Crusade, victor of the Battle of Bouvines",
          "answer": [
            "Philip II",
            "Philip Augustus"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Nomadic people to whom it sent Andre de Longjumeau and Rabban ben Sauma as ambassadors",
          "answer": "Mongols"
        },
        {
          "question": "1302 Battle at Courtrai that its forces lost against Flemish pikemen",
          "answer": "Battle of the Golden Spurs R"
        },
        {
          "question": "Son and successor of Louis X, both the youngest and the shortest-reigned king of France",
          "answer": [
            "John I",
            "John the Posthumous"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Scandal in which Queen Isabella of England denounced her sisters in law for adultery, leading to the end of the dynasty",
          "answer": [
            "Tour de Nesle affair",
            "Nesle’s Tower D T"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Boer Republics",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country that fought the Boer Republics in the Boer Wars F",
          "answer": [
            "United Kingdom",
            "U.K., Britain,",
            "England"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Country whose colonists created the Boer Republics and the Orange Free State",
          "answer": [
            "Netherlands",
            "the Dutch"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Capital of the South African Republic, named after a leader of the Voortrekkers",
          "answer": "Pretoria A"
        },
        {
          "question": "British colony that the South African Republic became after the Boer surrender",
          "answer": "Transvaal"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capital of the Orange Free State and birthplace of J.R.R. Tolkien",
          "answer": "Bloemfontein"
        },
        {
          "question": "Failed raid meant to get the Uitlanders to revolt in Boer territory",
          "answer": "Jameson Raid R"
        },
        {
          "question": "Boer general who negotiated the Treaty of Vereeniging with Lord Kitchener",
          "answer": "Jan Smuts"
        },
        {
          "question": "217-day siege in which Robert Baden-Powell was able to hold off the Boers",
          "answer": "Siege of Mafeking D T"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The newspaper The Daily Eagle was influential in the construction of this project. After this project’s supervisor fell ill with decomprFession sickness, his wife Emily took over as chief engineer. In an epic poem dedicated to this structure, (20 pts)",
        "Hart Crane described it as “across the harbor, silver-paced.” This structure’s integrity was tested when P.T. Barnum led 21 elephants across it as well as by Hurricane (10 pts)",
        "Sandy in 2012. This structure’s Park Row exit ran right under 1 Police Plaza and was closed after 9/11. For ten points, Chester A. Arthur opened what bridge linking Manhattan to a Long Island borough?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Brooklyn Bridge",
        "East River Bridge A"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Close to ten percent of the population of this country died during an 1866-1868 period known as the “great hunger years.” In 1827, this country’s “Mother Church” was burned in the Great Fire of (20 pts)",
        "Turku. Fredrik Idestam was an engineer from this country who founded a paper mill company in Tampere that would go on to become Nokia. The sortovuodet was a period of Russification partly inspired by (10 pts)",
        "Karelian nationalist movements in this country. For ten points, name this country, the home of notable artists such as Nobel Prize-winning author Frans Eemil Sillanpaa and composer Jean Sibelius."
      ],
      "answer": "Finland R"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man decided to walk an equivalent distance all around the world, ending at Guadalajara, Mexico, when he was released from prison. The Theory of Ruin Value was created by this man who posited that (20 pts)",
        "buildings should be designed to produce pleasing ruins. A famous photograph places this man with both his superior and sculptor Arno Breker in front of the (10 pts)",
        "Eiffel Tower. William Shirer claimed this architect did not, “shirk his responsibility and his guilt” towards war crimes. For ten points, name this minister of armaments who denied knowledge of the Holocaust and was known as “The Nazi who said sorry”. DANSWER: Albert Speer (4) A ship carrying gold to this modern country, the Doddington, was wrecked at Port Elizabeth. A general who fought in this country was called “heaven-born,” and that man selected Warren Hastings to be a resident before facing John (+) Burgoyne’s attacks over reforms. The Siege of Arcot took place in this country. Robert Clive made his fortune in this country where he beat Mir Jafar at the Battle of (*) Plassey. The French took Madras in, for ten points, what country where the United Kingdom controlled regions including Bengal?"
      ],
      "answer": "Republic of India T"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) While analyzing clerical and administrative workers, this author coined the term “white collar.” This man’s “Dead Hand” series includes a work that critiques newspaper moguls like William Randolph Hearst titled (20 pts)",
        "The Brass Check. After losing the 1934 California gubernatorial election, this man authored I, Candidate for Governor: And How I Got F Licked. Another work by this man led Congress to pass the (10 pts)",
        "Pure Food and Drug Act after detailing the horrors of Jurgus Rudkus and the Lithuanian immigrants in Chicago. For ten points, name this muckraker who wrote The Jungle."
      ],
      "answer": "Upton Sinclair"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this conflict, John Doukas was able to reassert his rule in Chios and Ephesus after the battle of Dorylaeum where the forces of Alp Arslan were decisively defeated. This A conflict’s leaders included Bohemond of Taranto and (20 pts)",
        "Godfrey of Bouillon, who were called to action after the battle of Manzikert resulted in the Seljuk Turks encroaching on the realms of (10 pts)",
        "Alexius I Komnenos, the Byzantine emperor. For ten points, Urban II called for what holy war during the Council of Clermont that ultimately placed Jerusalem in Christian hands?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "First Crusade",
        "Princes’ Crusade"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) After this figure’s father died, this figure asked Abu Bakr to relinquish the Sadak Oasis and refused to speak to him when he refused. This figure’s (20 pts)",
        "dowry was paid by a man whRo sold his shield but then had the shield returned as a wedding gift. Along with her husband, this woman is the common ancestor of all people claiming the title of “sayyid.” This woman was the only surviving child of (10 pts)",
        "Khadijah bint Khuwaylid. In Twelver Shia Islam, this figure is the only infallible woman. For ten points, name this wife of Ali and daughter of Muhammad."
      ],
      "answer": "Fatimah bint Muhammad"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man acquired a reputation for cruelty after flogging one of his merchant seaman and was forced to change his name to evade arrest after killing a mutinous crewman in a pay Ddispute. During raiding operations in the North and Irish Seas, this man’s sloop, the USS (20 pts)",
        "Ranger, captured the HMS Drake after a single ship duel. In the Battle of Flambough Head, this man’s ship fought the British HMS (10 pts)",
        "Serapis to a standstill, forcing its surrender. For ten points, name this legendary Revolutionary War commander of the Bon Homme Richard who reputedly said, “I have not yet begun to fight.”"
      ],
      "answer": "John Paul Jones T"
    }
  ]
}